# **ELIAS SPECTOR-ZABUSKY**

607-592-5831 | <u>elias.spector.zabusky@gmail.com</u> | Brooklyn, New York in <u>linkedin.com/in/elias-sz</u> | O github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy | Www.EliasSZ.com

### SUMMARY

Web developer, digital native, and musician working with the MERN stack, with an interest in backend development, product work, and databases. Graduate of Columbia's Coding Bootcamp with experience in **project management**, operations, and the arts. Strong skills in creative problem-solving and collaboration, partnered with a focus on flexibility, meticulousness, and camaraderie. Analytically minded with a knack for aiding decision-making.

#### **PROJECTS**

FRAiME | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/Fraime | www.FRAiMED.art

**Lead Developer.** FRAiME is an eCommerce platform still in development, leveraging OpenAI's DALL-E API to allow users to generate bespoke art and order high-quality prints. Future features include preprompting, finetuning options, and print ordering. **MERN** stack, **Next.js**, **Styled Components**.

- Co-planned the backend architecture and data flow; coded majority of REST API endpoints and db models.
- Collaborated on the design of the user interface, with a focus on customer experience and ease of use.

Dada Art Museum | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/dada-museum | dada-museum.herokuapp.com

**Lead Developer** and **UI Designer**. Proof of concept showcase project. Co-designed and implemented UI for a museum's homepage with a focus on functional and engaging features. **Node.js**, **React**, **Express**, **Chakra UI**.

- Coded Current Exhibits and Featured Artist sections; built reusable components for consistent site UX.
- Implemented random art feature, making calls to the Art Institute of Chicago's API on click or page load.

**Happiest Hour** | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/happiest-hour | happiest-hour-cb7f5c7640b4.herokuapp.com/

**Lead Developer** and **Concept Creator**. Site that allows a user to submit a zip code and receive the 12 highest-rated bars that advertise happy hour on Yelp. **Node.js**, **React**, **Express**, **Bootstrap**.

• Led backend work with Yelp's API; collaborated on frontend, particularly making the clock functional.

## **EDUCATION**

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Jan. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL ONLINE

Feb. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Business Analytics

BROWN UNIVERSITY, PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND

Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Arts and Performance Studies

Phi Beta Kappa; T. Carpenter Elocution Award

2011 - 2015

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, GraphQL, NoSQL Frontend: React, Chakra UI, Next.js, Styled Components, Handlebars, Vite Backend: MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL

Development Tools: VS Code, Figma, Insomnia, Chrome Dev Tools, Git, GitHub, Jest

Other: MS Excel, Google Analytics, Shopify, Chat GPT prompting

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN

Nov. 2015 - Present

Band-member, producer, songwriter, and/or arranger for a few NYC-based bands. www.stolenjars.com

## DIGITAL CONTENT AND MERCHANDISE MANAGER

Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2023

ROBIN BARON DESIGN: NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Led product-related operations for an interior designer's eCommerce business and acted as admin of the Shopify site. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop strategic plans for growth.

- Maintained and revised HTML and CSS for site as needed; added custom in-line CSS for blog features.
- Spearheaded the product upload for site launch, bringing the project up to speed in 6 weeks. In line with growth roadmap, managed a team of 8-10 freelancers in the upload of 12,500+ SKUs from ~40 vendors.

# INDEPENDENT EDITOR AND CONSULTANT, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Aug. 2017 – Jan. 2019

Offered editorial and writing services for resumes and cover letters, helping earn multiple clients' new jobs.